Cristian Silva

Software Developer / Database Engineer / Software Analyst

28 years old, married Skype: wd.cristian Email: wd.cristian@gmail.com Phone: +55 51 8156-7823 Page: http://goo.gl/ybhI7t LinkedIn: http://goo.gl/Gm4pkh

Highly qualified, tenacious, enthusiastic and well-accomplished IT professional, armed with broad-based background and skills in the areas of providing appropriate solution to business needs and problems. Training and display outstanding ability to plan, coordinate, implement practices and procedures to bring significant improvements in efficiency, productivity and technology processes, towards the successful attainment of organizational objectives and goals. Determined to implement earned skills and knowledge for the rapid growth of the prospective organization by working effectively and consistently, independently and under the pressure, as well as being a part of a team with excellent leadership skills.

Extensive experience as database engineer, designing and developing processes for information systems and corporate data. Strong SQL skills for data validation, analysis, and DDL script generation for DBA teams. Extensive experience to create web systems with complex and dynamic layouts always looking for the best usability. Outsourced development for companies using SAP, Totvs and others.

Skills

- T-SQL: Advanced 8 years experience
- Database engineer: 8 years experience
- Javascript: Advanced 6 years experience
- JQuery: Advanced 6 years experience
- PHP: Advanced 3 years experience
- SQL Server Administration and Automation:
- Advanced 2 years experience
- HTML5 / CSS3: Advanced
- C# / ASP.Net: Intermediate 3 years experience
- Team and Project Management: Intermediate
 - 2 years experience
- English: Intermediate

Education / Qualifications

- Leadership and Development (coach) Training: INEXH, RS Brazil (2016)
- Technologist Degree in System Analysis and Development: FAQI, RS Brazil (2014)
- SAP Hana database for Startups: SAP, RS Brazil (2013)
- 6234 MS SQL Server 2008 Analysis Services: Ka Solutions, SP Brazil (2012)
- 6235 MS SQL Server 2008 Integration Services: Ka Solutions, SP Brazil (2012)
- 6236 MS SQL Server 2008 Reporting Services: Ka Solutions, SP Brazil (2012)
- Oracle 10g: ULBRA, RS Brazil (2008)
- Computer Technician Degree: QI Technical Schools, RS Brazil (2008)

Experience

Full-Stack Developer

CWI Software 6/2015 - Present

Worked as part of a team that developed a highly complex system for a Brazilian bank. This system is
responsible for credit and debit transactions in current accounts and generates indicators that assist in the
company's decision-making.

• Restructured the billing system that includes a data model, performance improvement, and increasing flexibility to the business.

Technologies: C#, JavaScript, Reporting Services, MSSQL Server, SQL Server Tuning Advisor, Oracle DB, Jenkins

Co-Owner / Project Manager / Full-Stack Developer

Q3 Performance Solutions

10/2014 - Present

- Worked as a full-stack developer and developed a system that gets data in real-time from measuring machines and analyzing dimensional deviant symptoms, generating alerts, historic charts and statistics in very-friendly and customizable dashboards.
- The system reduced the cost of a multinational car manufacturer's recall in half a million dollars per month.

Technologies: C#, .NET Framework, MSSQL Server, JavaScript, jQuery, Highcharts, CSS3, HTML5

Professor

QI Technical schools

01/2010 - 12/2011 and 06/2015 - 05/2016

• Created educational content, activities, and projects for students of varying levels of age and knowledge on systems development in the field of of computer tech.

Technologies: Java, T-SQL, HTML, CSS3, PHP, Android Studio

Full-Stack Developer

NC Production Management Systems

01/2010 - 10/2014

- Created a multiplatform terminal to get data from machines or employees of factory floor and generate dashboards to decision making of production segmentation.
- Developed a friendly and customizable web system to provide data in real-time.
- Created a communication layer between client ERP (TOTVS, SAP) and company system.

Technologies: PHP, MSSQL Server, C#, .NET Framework, JavaScript, jQuery, Highcharts

Application Support and Implementation

Numericon Manufacturing Systems

08/2007 - 12/2009

• Implemented and supported 25 projects including national and multinational companies.

Technologies: T-SQL, Visual Basic 6